FRANCISCO DO VALE

Front-End Developer

Caucaia, CE, Brazil | +55 85 99182 5226

<u>linkedin.com/in/franciscovale</u> | <u>fdovalejr@gmail.com</u>

PROFILE

Front-end developer with 5+ years of experience in this area. Strong skills in the front-end base (HTML, CSS, and Javascript), hands-on experience with component libraries (e.g Angular Material, Bootstrap), CSS preprocessors (e.g. SASS, Stylus), and since 2017 working with the new Angular framework. An effective team player, a very open-minded and adaptable person with a keen eye for detail.

SKILLS

Html5, css3, javascript, angular, jquery, bootstrap, material angular, sass, stylus, git.

EXPERIENCE

ALTRAN, Porto, Portugal

Dec 2020 - Present

Front-End Developer

Work as a contractor to the company clients. From finance to telehealthcare.

- Implement new features on the system using Angular framework..
- Work in a cross-functional team using SCRUM.

Development stack: Angular 11, RxJS, SCSS.

MazzaFC, Fortaleza, Brazil

Jun 2020 - Nov/2020

Front-End Developer

Work as a contractor to the company clients. From finance to telehealthcare.

- Implement new features on the system using Angular framework and NGRX as a state management library.
- Work in a cross-functional team using SCRUM.
- Working with Svelte for an app used on Point of Sale machines.

Development stack: Angular 8, Material Angular, SCSS, NGRX, Svelte.

EPAM SYSTEMS, Katowice, Poland

Aug 2019 - Mar 2020

Front-End Developer

Worked as front-end developer implementing front-end code with Angular framework, according to business requirement documents and prototypes.

- Implement high-quality, well-tested front-end code using Angular framework and NGRX as a state management library.
- Work in a cross-functional team using SCRUM.

Development stack: Angular 7, Material Angular, SCSS, and NGRX.

Jun 2018 - Jul 2019

Front-End Developer

Worked in several internal systems downsizing. They are migrating all the medical records and health program systems from PL-SQL to the new architecture using Java/Angular 2+.

- Implementation of new features and systems.
- Restyle of the UI according to Material Design guidelines.
- Created a seed project for faster new project creation.

Development stack: Angular 4/6/7, Material Angular, Bootstrap, and SCSS.

EICON, Fortaleza, Brazil

Mar 2018 - Jun 2018

Front-End Developer

Worked as a front-end developer using Angular framework.

- Adapt a generic project to the client's needs.
- Implement a readable and good front-end code.

Development stack: Angular 4, Bootstrap, SCSS.

CTIS, Fortaleza, Brazil

Jun 2017 - Fev 2018

UI Developer

Worked as a front-end developer using Angular framework.

- Developed the front-end code based on client requirements.
- Implemented new visual guidelines for future projects on the client.

Development stack: Angular 4, Material Angular, Bootstrap Grid, and SCSS.

IFACTORY, Fortaleza, Brazil

Mar 2017 - May 2017

UI Developer (Contractor)

Worked as a freelancer front-end to build an NGO institutional page according to PSD layouts.

- Implementation of front-end code from PSD layouts.
- Integration of generated static files with Adobe AEM platform.

Development stack: HTML5, CSS3, Handlebars.JS, Styllus, Gulp, jQuery and Bootstrap.

SELLETIVA, Fortaleza, Brazil

Nov 2015 - May 2016

Trainee Web Developer

Worked as a web developer in the whole stack of the product.

- Implemented new functionalities.
- Implemented full-stack code.
- Investigate business requirements.
- Integration with external partner projects.

Development stack: Angular.JS, Bootstrap, Styllus, jQuery, Lodash, PHP, Zend Framework.

UNIFOR. Fortaleza. Brazil

Jun 2015 - May 2016

Trainee Mobile Developer

Worked as a trainee focused on mobile development for Android OS.

• Development of new functionalities.

- Meet with clients for requirements gathering.
- Implementation of low fidelity prototypes.
- Implementation of POC's (Proof of Concept) to test the new technologies proposed.

Development stack: Java for Android.

LAYOUT SYSTEMS, Fortaleza, Brazil

2013 - 2015

IT Assistant

EDUCATION

University of Fortaleza, Fortaleza, Brazil

2014 - 2017

Associate's Degree in Systems Analysis and Development

LANGUAGES

• English: Speaking B2, Writing B2.

• French: General A1.

• Portuguese: Native.